Toggle navigation     MENU [Washington Community and Technical Colleges](https://www.sbctc.edu/default.aspx)

SearchClick to Search

* Search  Click to Search

Privacy Policy
==============

[Home](https://www.sbctc.edu/) >  Privacy Policy

Thank you for visiting the Washington State Board for Community and Technical College (SBCTC) website. Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy, we've developed this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used within our sites and services.

SBCTC reserves the right to revise and update this Privacy Notice at any time without notice by posting such revised Privacy Notice at the SBCTC home page.

Contact Us
----------

To request correction of factual errors in your personally identifiable information, offer comments about the SBCTC website or about the information in this Privacy Notice, contact SBCTC:

Washington State Board for Community and Technical Colleges  
ATTN: Webmaster  
PO Box 42495  
Olympia, WA 98504-2495

Phone: 360-704-4400

Email: [webmaster@sbctc.edu](mailto:webmaster@sbctc.edu)

Expand All

-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

If you do nothing during your visit except to browse or download information, we automatically collect and store the following information about your visit:

* The internet Protocol Address and domain name is used, but not the email address. The internet Protocol address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your internet service provider or directly to your computer. We use the internet Protocol Address to direct internet traffic to you;
* The type of browser and operating system you used;
* The date and time you visited this site;
* The web pages or services you accessed at this site, and;
* Information is collected for site management and summary statistical purposes. This is used for such purposes as evaluating determining technical design specifications and identifying system performance or problem areas.

For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, SBCTC-supported computer systems employ software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. Except for authorized law enforcement investigations and the security purposes mentioned elsewhere in this notice, no other attempts are made to identify individual users or their usage habits. Base data logs are used for no other purposes and are scheduled for regular destruction in accordance with public records retention schedules (Chapter 40.14 RCW).

Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information on this service are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the state Computer Trespass law (RCW 9A.52.110) and federal statutes including the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act.

If you send an email during your visit to the SBCTC website, the server may retain the email message and email address. We use your email address to respond appropriately to your request. This may be to address issues you identify, to further improve our website, or to forward the email for appropriate action.

The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include attachments such as documents, audio, video, and graphic information formats you send us. The information is retained in accordance with Chapter 40.14 RCW, Preservation and Destruction of Public Records.

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

On occasion, we may work with third parties using cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies to collect or receive information from this website, its related social media, and associated web applications and use that information to provide measurement services and targeted ads. This helps us promote our website and programs to those who have already shown an interest. You may opt out of this collection and use of information for ad targeting at any time. Learn more at [Understanding Online Advertising](https://youradchoices.com/control).

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------

"Personal information" is information about a natural person that is readily identifiable to that specific individual. Personal information includes such things as an individual's name, address, and phone number. A domain name or internet Protocol address is not considered personal information.

We collect no personal information about you unless you voluntarily participate in an activity that asks for information (i.e. sending an email). If you choose not to participate in these activities, your choice will in no way effect your ability to use any other feature of this website.

If personal information is requested on the website or volunteered by the user, state law and the federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it. However, this information is a public record once you provide it, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by federal or state law.

The SBCTC website is a general audience site and we do not knowingly collect any personal information from children. Users are cautioned that the collection of personal information requested from or volunteered by children online or by email will be treated the same as information given by an adult, and may be subject to public access.

### Access and correction of personal information

Many of the online services we provide allow you to manage your personal information. You can review any personal information we collect about you. You may recommend changes to your personal information you believe in error by submitting a written request that credibly shows the error. If you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than what was intended when submitted, you may contact us. In all cases, we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.

-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

In the State of Washington, laws exist to ensure that government is open and that the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed by state government. At the same time, there are exceptions to the public's right to access public records that serve various needs including the privacy of individuals. Exceptions are provided by both state and federal laws.

As a public agency, all our information is governed by laws such as Washington’s Public Records Act \[[RCW Chapter 42.56](https://apps.leg.wa.gov/RCW/default.aspx?cite=42.56)\], as well as privacy laws. Information sent to SBCTC or collected through use of this site may become a public record, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not otherwise protected by federal or state law.

### Nondisclosure for commercial use

Pursuant to [RCW 42.56.070](https://apps.leg.wa.gov/RCW/default.aspx?cite=42.56.070)(8), SBCTC will not give, sell, or provide access to any list of persons for any commercial purpose. Commercial use of lists (individuals or directories including — but not limited to — name, address, phone, email) provided at this site is prohibited.

In the event of a conflict between this Privacy Notice and the Public Records Act or other law governing the disclosure of records, the Public Records Act or other applicable law will prevail.

------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Except where noted in the [SBCTC Website Terms of Use](https://www.sbctc.edu/terms-of-use.aspx), content on this site is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License. This site also contains text, artwork, photos or other content that may be copyrighted by others and is being used by permission.

See the [SBCTC Website Terms of Use: Copyright and Open Licensing and Code of Conduct for Adopting Content](https://www.sbctc.edu/terms-of-use.aspx) sections for appropriate use and citation guidelines.

----------------------------------------------------------

SBCTC, as developer and manager of this website, has taken several steps to safeguard the integrity of its telecommunications and computing infrastructure, including but not limited to authentication, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. Security measures have been integrated into the design, implementation and day-to-day practices of the entire SBCTC operating environment as part of its continuing commitment to risk management.

This information should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided via SBCTC supported websites.

------------------------------------------------------------

The SBCTC website links to other websites. These include links to websites operated by other government agencies, educational organizations, and non-profit organizations. When you link to another site, you are no longer on the SBCTC website and this Privacy Notice will not apply. When you link to another website, you are subject to the privacy policy of that site.

Neither the State of Washington, nor any agency, officer, or employee of the State of Washington warrants the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published by this system, nor endorses any content, viewpoints, products, or services linked from this system, and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from this system does so at his or her own risk.

The SBCTC reserves the right to revise and update this Privacy Notice at any time without notice by posting such revised Privacy Notice at the SBCTC home page.

 Washington State Board for Community and Technical Colleges

 Except where otherwise noted in our [Terms of Use](https://www.sbctc.edu/terms-of-use.aspx), content on this website is licensed under a [Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/).
